

Nelson Nunes

Senior Full Stack Software Developer Cape Town, South Africa

I am a multifaceted, passionate and enthusiastic individual who started my programming career because of my hate for computers. At the start of my higher education (and typical of most students), my focus reflected in my results. After failing to secure a secondary "Parental Bursary", I started my employment career. To keep my mind stimulated, I decided to do a short course and, hating computers, I picked C & C++ programming. I fell in love with the art of programming. I see programming as an artform. With the screen my canvas, the code my brushes, I embraced the journey of coding art. After 14 years of a genuinely illustrious career in software development, I fell on hard times & find myself unemployed. I undertake to follow my dreams once again and begin my journey as an entrepreneurial renegade. Entrepreneurship is no walk in the park & one of the unavoidable side effects that goes along with an entrepreneur, is failure & loss. While some may let failure knock them down, and I was no different, I have always kept getting up, learning and growing. "I didn't fail the test, I just found 100 ways to do it wrong" - Benjamin Franklin.

Experience

Senior Software Developer

iOCO

Cape Town, South Africa (Fully Remote) Nov 2019 - Dec 2022

Outsourced to:

- 1) Sanlam
- 2) Anglo American
- 3) Vodacom
- 4) Capricorn

Senior Software Developer Sanlam

Cape Town, South Africa (Remote) Nov 2019 - Dec 2020

Entrepreneur

Oteka

Johannesburg, South Africa Oct 2018 - Oct 2019

Uber Driver/Partner UBER

Johannesburg, South Africa
Oct 2016 - Oct 2018
1663 trips completed.
One of the highest rated Uber Drivers in South Africa, with a rating of 4.9

Entrepreneur

Oteka

Johannesburg, South Africa

Education

West Ridge High School

Matric

1991 - 1996

Boston City Campus

Certificate

1999 - 1999

C & C++ Programming

Microsoft

Certificate

2000 - 2000

MVP - Visual Basic 6.0

Alexander Forbes

Certificate

2010 - 2010

COBIT 5.0

Alexander Forbes

Certificate

2010 - 2010

ITIL 3.0

Alexander Forbes

Certificate

2012 - 2012

SCRUM

Senior Solutions Developer/Consultant

Asyst International

Johannesburg, South Africa Oct 2012 - Mar 2014

Senior Software Developer

Alexander Forbes

Johannesburg, South Africa Jan 2011 - Sep 2012

Senior Software Developer

Alexander Forbes (UK)

Johannesburg, South Africa Feb 2010 - Dec 2011

Senior Software Developer

Alexander Forbes

Johannesburg, South Africa Jan 2008 - Jan 2010

Intermediate Software Developer

Dimension Data

Johannesburg, South Africa Oct 2005 - Dec 2007

Software Developer

The Workforce Group

Johannesburg, South Africa Oct 1999 - Sep 2005

Skills

.NET Framework

.NET Core

Angular

JavaScript

Typescript

Contact

nelson@nelsonunes.dev

+27 65 889 6633

Cape Town, South Africa

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nelsonunes/ https://github.com/nelsonunes-dev

Titips.//gitilab.com/Ticisonaries av

https://nelsonunes.dev